pagefair.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy and Cookie Policy | PageFair

PageFair Limited and its subsidiaries ( **“We”** ) support online privacy, and are committed to protecting your privacy rights. This policy (together with our General [Terms and Conditions](https://pagefair.com/conditions)) sets out how any information we collect about you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.

For the purpose of the Irish Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003 (the **“Acts”** ), the data controller is PageFair Limited a company incorporated in Ireland with company number 530978 whose registered office is at Unit D, Mountpleasant Business Centre, Mountpleasant Avenue, Dublin 6, D06 N925, Ireland.

### General Information about Cookies, SessionStorage and LocalStorage

Cookies, SessionStorage and LocalStorage are standardised ways for a website to store a small file of letters and numbers in your browser. These are typically used to remember your preferences, perform security checks, perform analytics, to recognise you as a unique user as you move from one page to another, and to issue you with a secret key when you login that authorises you to access areas of the website that are specific to you or only viewable to logged in users.

By default, it is not possible for one website to access the first-party cookies, LocalStorage or SessionStorage stored by another website, however if two websites make requests to the same third-party web domain, then that third party can store a cookie on the one website and access it on the other (these are known as “third party cookies”). Third party cookies that contain unique values can potentially be used to track you between websites that make requests to the third party.

Cookies are typically automatically deleted when you close your browser, or when their specified expiry date is reached. SessionStorage files are automatically deleted when you close your browser. LocalStorage are deleted when the website that stored them deletes them.  You can also delete cookies and other storage from your browser at any time you like by visiting your web browser settings.

Different web browsers provide varying degrees of control over your browser’s cookies, SessionStorage and LocalStorage.  You can change your browser settings, or if necessary change to a different browser, to automatically prevent 3rd party cookies from being stored. If you are concerned about online tracking you can also change your settings to send a “[Do-Not-Track](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Do_Not_Track)” signal to request websites not to use cookies or other mechanisms to track you, or you can install a browser extension such as [Disconnect](https://disconnect.me/) or [Ghostery](https://www.ghostery.com/) to block 3rd party tracking cookies on websites.

## The PageFair Website

The PageFair website (currently hosted at [https://pagefair.com](https://pagefair.com/)) includes the PageFair corporate website, the Publisher Console, the PageFair blog, and other content and online tools as may be modified from time to time (the **“Website”** ). Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it when you are interacting with the Website.

Our Website contains social sharing buttons and links to and from other websites.  Please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

## Information We May Collect on our Website

When you use our Website, We may collect and process information about you in the following ways.

| Information | Purpose | Retention  
---|---|---|---  
Correspondence | Contact information and correspondence | If you contact us, we may keep a record of the correspondence for future reference. | Indefinite  
Mailing lists | Email address, name, any other information provided on subscription | If you subscribe to one of our mailing lists, we will use your subscription information to send you emails corresponding to the topics you have subscribed to be contacted about. | Until you unsubscribe from the mailing list.  
General web forms | Various | If you provide us with any other information by submitting a form, we will retain and use this information for the specified purpose. | Retained until you request deletion of the information, or as otherwise specified when we collect the information.  
Usage logs | Anonymous information relating to your visits to the Website including, but not limited to, the IP address from which you accessed the website, information about your device type, operating system type and browser type, URLs you access on the Website, and timestamps | Website access logs and similar information may be used for system administration, debugging, security analysis or improving the availability or usability of our Website. 

This information may also be aggregated to create anonymous statistics about the use of our Website

| Usage logs may be retained for 52 weeks.  
Aggregated information may be retained indefinitely.  
Publisher Console | Email address, name, a password, organisation name, organisation details, billing, payment and tax information,  your website address(es) and other information as is necessary to provide the requested services. 

Records of your interactions with the Publisher Console.

| You may register on the Website to use the Publisher Console by accepting the _Publisher Terms and Conditions_ , which you should refer to for additional privacy information when using our services. 

We may also keep a record of your interactions with the Publisher Console to help us improve our service and to contact you with information about our services.

| We may retain personal information including email address, nam and password for the duration of your agreement with us under the Publisher Terms and Conditions.  
Non-personal data such as organisation name, billing information, tax information and website addresses will be retained indefinitely.   
  
## PageFair Website Cookies and Storage

The Website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website, to enable you to leave comments on our blog, and also allows us to improve our site with analytics. By continuing to browse the site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.

The cookies that may be stored when you visit the Website are detailed below.

| Type | Name | Possible Values | Purpose | Expiry | More Info  
---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
Session cookie | 1st party | PHPSESSID | Unique number | To identify you as a unique user as you move from page to page on the website | When you close your web browser. |   
Cloudflare CDN Cookie | 1st party | __cfduid | Unique number | To enhance website security by distinguishing between trusted users and untrusted users sharing a single IP address. | 365 days | [more info](https://support.cloudflare.com/hc/en-us/articles/200170156-What-does-the-Cloudflare-cfduid-cookie-do-)  
Google analytics cookie | 1st party | _ga | Unique number | Used to count unique visitors | 2 years | [more info](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)  
Google analytics cookie | 1st party | _gid | Unique number | Use to count unique visitors per day | 24 hours | [more info](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)  
Google analytics cookie | 1st party | _gat | 1 | Used to throttle requests to google analytics | 1 minute | [more info](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)  
PageFair Analytics | 1st party | bm_daily_unique  
bm_sample_frequency | Predefined values | Used to count the number of visitors to the website who use adblocking software and to throttle requests to PageFair servers. | End of day | See “Services”  
PageFair Analytics | 1st party | bm_last_load_status | Boolean | Used to detect visitors who enable or disable their adblocking software  | Never | See “Services”  
PageFair Analytics | 1st party | bm_monthly_unique | Predefined value | Used to count the number of visitors to the website who use adblocking software | End of month | See “Services”  
PageFair Analytics | 3rd party | d_uniq | Predefined value: “True” | Used to count the number of unique visitors per day on all PageFair sites | End of day | See “Services”  
PageFair Analytics | 3rd party | m_uniq | Predefined value: “True” | Used to count the number of unique visitors per month on all PageFair sites | End of month | See “Services”  
Cookie Consent | 1st party | consentDirective | Predefined value: 1 | Used to remember when a user has accepted PageFair’s cookie use notice | 365 days |   
Session ID | 1st party | sessionid | Unique value | Issued to you by the PageFair Console to allow you to create an account or to log in | 7 days |   
Cross-Site Request Forgery Protection | 1st party | csrftoken | Unique value | Issued by the PageFair Console to protect against online forms being submitted from unauthorised locations | 365 days or until you submit a form |   
  
### Disclosure of Information

We may disclose your personal data to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 155 of the Irish Companies Acts, 1963.

We may disclose your personal data to third parties:

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If PageFair Limited or a substantial part of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our _General[Terms and Conditions of Use](https://pagefair.com/conditions/)_ and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of PageFair Limited, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.
  * Where you give us permission to do so.

Other than the above limited circumstances we will never disclose your data to any third party.

### Where we Store Your Personal Data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination inside or outside the European Economic Area ( **“EEA”** ). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will follow commercially reasonable best practices to encrypt your access to our Website and to prevent unauthorised access to your personal data, you transmit your data to us at your own risk.

### User Rights

You have the right to ask us not to process personal data for marketing purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by:

  * Choosing not to subscribe to be contacted on the forms on the Website
  * Opting out using the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any marketing email we send to you
  * Contacting us

The Acts gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Acts. Any access request may be subject to a fee of €6.35 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

## The PageFair Services

PageFair provides online analysis and advertising services (the **“Services”** ) to the publishers of various 3rd party websites who have accepted the PageFair Publisher Terms and Conditions. PageFair may process information about the visitors to these 3rd party websites on behalf of the publishers who have contracted with us. PageFair may process the following anonymous information about visitors to websites that make use of the Services. For more details about the use of the Services by a website, please refer to that website’s own privacy policy, or contact that website.

| Information | Purpose | Retention  
---|---|---|---  
Analytics | We will detect the usage of adblock software, store non-unique information using cookies or LocalStorage, and collect aggregate statistics about this usage for reporting. | To help website publishers understand the usage of adblock software by visitors to their website, and to generate overall market statistics about adblock usage. | Aggregated data may be retained indefinitely.  
Advertising | Random first-party user ID, specific to each website. | PageFair stores a unique, random, first-party user ID to enable advertisers to perform frequency capping, so that a given ad is not displayed too often to any one user on a website. A different ID is given on each website, which means this ID cannot be used by PageFair for cross-site tracking. | The user ID is automatically deleted 30 days after it is first created.  
Business Intelligence | We may also collect aggregate metrics about visitors’ browsers, devices and onsite behaviour. | To track aggregate statistics about browser technology usage, to create business intelligence for PageFair or for partners, to measure the amount of advertising that is displayed by PageFair on each website. | Aggregated data may be retained indefinitely.  
  
### Server-Side Rendering

PageFair Advertising works by performing server-side rendering on 3rd party javascript creatives from advertisers. This means that javascript from unapproved 3rd parties never executes in the web browsers of visitors to websites that use the Services, which effectively prevent the risk of vistors being exposed to malvertising or unauthorised tracking.

### User Matching

PageFair may help advertising partners improve the relevance of advertising on websites that make use of the Services by performing user matching. User matching permits an advertising partner to recognise when a random first-party user ID from PageFair corresponds to a user ID (and any associated advertising targeting data) that the partner already holds. PageFair’s user matching functionality is performed in such a way that no information about the URLs that are visited by users is communicated to the advertising partners, and it is automatically deactivated for users who have expressed privacy preferences using Do-Not-Track settings or similar privacy tools, in their web browsers.

### PageFair Service Cookies and LocalStorage

When you visit a website that uses the Services, various cookies and LocalStorage files may be stored in your browser. The data that may be stored is described below.

| Type | Name | Possible Values | Purpose | Expiry  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
PageFair Analytics | 1st party | bm_last_load_status | Boolean | Used to count the number of visitors to the website who use adblocking software | Never  
PageFair Analytics | 1st party | bm_monthly_unique | Predefined value | Used to count the number of visitors to the website who use adblocking software | End of month  
PageFair Analytics | 3rd party | d_uniq | Predefined value: “True” | Used to count the number of unique visitors per day on all PageFair sites | End of day  
PageFair Analytics | 3rd party | m_uniq | Predefined value: “True” | Used to count the number of unique visitors per month on all PageFair sites | End of month  
PageFair Advertising | LocalStorage (1st party) | adonisUid | Unique value | Used to permit frequency capping of advertising, so that advertisers can prevent the same ad from being displayed too many times to a user on a website | 30 days  
PageFair Advertising | LocalStorage (1st party) | adonisUidExpiry | Timestamp | The date on which the adonisUid setting will be expired. | Never  
PageFair Advertising | LocalStorage (1st party) | adonisCookieSyncExpiry | Timestamp | The next date and time after which user matching should be performed | Never  
PageFair Advertising | LocalStorage (1st party) | adonisClientOptions | Predefined values | Website configuration options | Never  
  
### PageFair Services and Do-Not-Track

We are committed to respecting privacy preferences have have been expressed by visitors to websites that use the Services. The Services do not employ 3rd party tracking cookies, and are configured to disable user matching or gathering of traffic data in relation to any user who has enabled privacy settings that We can detect with commercially reasonable effort (in which case advertising will still be displayed, but will not be targeted by advertisers to the interests of individual users). We currently detect the usage of “Do-Not-Track”, or browser extensions such as [Disconnect](https://disconnect.me/) or [Ghostery](https://www.ghostery.com/), or the Firefox web browser’s “private browsing” mode, or use of the “EasyPrivacy” list in the Adblock or Adblock Plus browser extensions. To opt out of user matching and processing of traffic information, please configure or install one of the above alternatives.

## Changes to This Privacy Policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page.

## Contact

You may contact us at any time using the form located at <https://pagefair.com/contact/>.
